JOHN COLELLA

4 631 838 8222

₱ Brooklyn, NY

in

www.linkedin.com/in/johnmcolella

• https://github.com/jmcolella

Summary

I am a web developer skilled in building apps using Ruby, JavaScript, Rails, Sinatra, Bootstrap and Materialize. I have a passion for design and love working the full stack to create meaningful projects. With experience working in fast-paced environments, I'm a team player who can work efficiently with others to meet hard deadlines. I have excellent communication and organizational skills along with analytical experience that has proven effective in collaborative environments.

Skills

LANGUAGES

Ruby

JavaScript(JQuery)

HTML5

CSS3

SQL

FRAMEWORKS

Rails

Jekyll

Bootstrap

Materialize

Sinatra

React.js

DATABASES

PostgresSQL

ActiveRecord

SQLite

TESTING

RSpec

Jasmine

Capybara

PLATFORMS

Google Maps API

Yelp API

Twitter API

METHODOLOGIES

Object Oriented Design Test Driven Development

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

Italian

Projects

LOCALEYES

http://www.localeyestrips.com

An app that connects tourists to day trips curated by locals. Made in 7 days as a group project.

- Built with Ruby on Rails back end and Materialize fron tend frameworks (Materialize is based on the Google Material Design philosophy)
- · Incorporate Google Maps and Google Places API to retrieve information for created day trips
- · Assist with set up of Google Maps integration into web app and logic behind pulling information from Google
- · Use JQuery and AJAX for commenting, favoriting and communicating with Google Places API
- Responsible for styling and organizing inbox and messaging system between users; made use of the Mailboxer gem
- Assist with the set up of Facebook OAuth and implementation of Devise security gem

HOPSEARCH

https://hopsearch.herokuapp.com/

A web app that allows users to search for numerous hop varietals and learn more about their attributes

- Built with Ruby on Rails 4 back end and React.js views on the front end. Utilize the Bootstrap 3 CSS framework for styling
- Incorporate the BreweryDB API for hop information as well as the Google Maps API to display a map of major hop
 growing regions
- · Complete research to fill in missing gaps in BreweryDB API to create a unique information database for users
- Fully tested models, controllers and routes with RSpec

256: A 2048 CLONE

https://github.com/jmcolella/2048-clone

A clone of the popular game 2048.

- Built using vanilla JavaScript along with the JQuery and Underscore.js libraries.
- Use object-oriented principles to compose game and determine logic for winning or losing the game.

Employment

KATTEN MUCHIN ROSENMAN LLP

New York, NY Iun 2013 to Mar 2016

Paralega

- · Partner with leadership and associates to secure loans for multi-million dollar real estate investments.
- · Manage the organization and transferral of legal documents between attorneys and clients.
- · Liaise with internal and external parties to ensure post-closing procedures and deadlines were secured.
- Analyze legal documentation to facilitate drafting new documents for future projects.
- Oversee the integration and training of new paralegal hires into the firm.

TRIBECA FILM

New York, NY Jan 2015 to Aug 2015

Acquisitions/Marketing Intern

- · Generate performance reports for video-on-demand data to understand national market for Tribeca Film titles.
- Compile master revenue report of external independent titles for leadership to determine market size for competitor's titles.
- Analyze marketing practices of major video-on-demand vendors to best strategize promotion of Tribeca titles with these vendors.
- Take lead on portions of marketing outreach by analyzing social media statistics to determine best business partners for particular Tribeca titles.

MAGNOLIA PICTURES

New York, NY Jan 2013 to May 2013

Marketing/Publicity Interi

- Serve as first point-of-contact and main liaison for guests via e-mail, phone and at the Magnolia office front desk.
- Compile press information regarding Magnolia releases for marketing to track performance of Magnolia titles.
- Research business contacts for targeted Magnolia releases and update database with information for future use.
- Set up promotional materials, prepared a theater and ushered guests as part of a Magnolia premiere screening.

IFC FILMS

New York, NY Sep 2011 to May 2012

Acquisitions Intern

- Write coverage on films and scripts as part of the evaluation process for choosing films for distribution under the IFC label.
- · Attend Tribeca Film Festival as a junior member of the Acquisitions team to screen and evaluate competition films.
- Organize and update IFC's master database of past and future films to facilitate research process on potential films to acquire.
- Draft itineraries for executives and coordinate necessary accommodations with hospitality and transportation services.

Education

COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY IN THE CITY OF NEW YORK

B.A. Film Studies 2013

Thesis: The tradition of "mono no aware" in the films of Yasujiro Ozu.

DEV BOOTCAMP

2016

19-week intensive program focusing on competencies in Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails.